<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>svankmajer's blog</title>
  <subtitle>a learning logbook</subtitle>
  <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/</id>
  <link href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/"/>
  <link href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-05-31T18:19:00-03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>svankmajer</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Psychlopedia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/31/understanding-psychlopedia/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/31/understanding-psychlopedia/</id>
    <published>2014-05-31T18:19:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-03T13:36:45-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the past weeks, I started to question myself about one of my current endeavors: &lt;a href="http://psiclopedia.svankmajer.net/"&gt;Psychlopedia&lt;/a&gt;.
I want to get a thorough comprehension of what I am trying to accomplish with the time and resources I am putting into this project. Know 
what can be done, thus find out and test what could or should be done to finally &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; what must be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No fooling around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to make clear that I don&amp;#39;t know for certain any of what I will be talking about in this post. This is an exploratory exercise to me, and it
should be so for you too, so please bear that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reading &lt;a href="http://thoughtbot.com/"&gt;thoughtbot&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://playbook.thoughtbot.com/"&gt;Playbook&lt;/a&gt; when I stumbled on Product Design Sprints, an amazing 
concept developed by the &lt;a href="http://www.gv.com/design/"&gt;Google Ventures&amp;#39; design team&lt;/a&gt;. 
Essentially, a Product Design Sprint is a technique that increases the chance of channeling efforts into meaningful and sustainable productions. 
Please read thoughtbot&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/the-product-design-sprint"&gt;amazing article&lt;/a&gt; on this subject which explains it to the detail 
perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I am stressing the following question: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f84LymEs67Y"&gt;&amp;#39;what job is the user hiring the product to do?&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a question proposed by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clayton_M._Christensen"&gt;Clayton Christensen&lt;/a&gt;, a Business Administration professor at
Harvard Business School. Having asked myself about this not even once in my own product design path, I was really intrigued. So I grabbed my coat
and went out for a random walk (&lt;em&gt;on a Hidden Markov chain&lt;/em&gt;), my regular deep thinking session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking down Colegiales, I started to identify three possible jobs Psychlopedia in its current conception could do and do pretty well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Feed our curiosity and increase the quality of its by-products&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Connect us to others through our inner experiences&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Lessen our fear and/or anxiety towards psychonautics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am trying to finish the critical path based on these assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a work-in-progress and part of a series on product design focused on Psychlopedia, a digital archive of psychedelic experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reborn</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/29/reborn/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/29/reborn/</id>
    <published>2014-05-29T12:46:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-29T17:15:57-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great plans for the weekend! On saturday I will be attending the weekly meetup of &lt;a href="http://www.congresointeractivo.org/"&gt;Congreso Interactivo&lt;/a&gt; at 
the Barracas Public Library &lt;a href="http://www.bibliobarracas.com.ar/hacklab/"&gt;Hacklab&lt;/a&gt; here in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CI is a &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; civic engagement organisation devoted to social research and the development of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_government"&gt;open goverment&lt;/a&gt; tools to improve the exercise of governance towards a better democracy. They have released upstanding apps like &lt;a href="http://www.elegilegi.org/"&gt;Elegilegi&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="http://www.decadavotada.com.ar/"&gt;Decada Votada&lt;/a&gt;, drawing attention of &lt;a href="http://www.lanacion.com.ar/1604004-como-votarias-siendo-diputado"&gt;local&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="https://source.opennews.org/en-US/articles/decada-votada-news-app-track-voting-records/"&gt;international&lt;/a&gt; news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was a teenager I dream of being part of a open goverment initiative and I think this is a great opportunity for me to add up to a team effort 
towards the envision and effective implementation of an open democracy in Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M-x start-hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
