<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>svankmajer's blog</title>
  <subtitle>a learning logbook</subtitle>
  <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/</id>
  <link href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/"/>
  <link href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-06-26T01:50:00-03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>svankmajer</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Rake 0.9</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/26/rake-0-9/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/26/rake-0-9/</id>
    <published>2014-06-26T01:50:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-26T02:05:59-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just found out about something cool introduced on Rake 0.9. Take a look at this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="highlight shell"&gt;&lt;span class="gp"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;rake -W publish
rake publish  /home/svankmajer/.rvm/gems/ruby-2.1.2@rants/../gh-pages.rake:65:in &lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;top &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;required&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeap, &lt;code&gt;rake -W &amp;lt;task&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; resolves to where the task is defined. You can also run it without parameters and see that output for all available tasks. Pretty 
solid.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Git - Stashing (annex)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/04/git-stash/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/04/git-stash/</id>
    <published>2014-06-04T15:12:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-04T17:13:19-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You all know about good ol&amp;#39; &lt;code&gt;git-stash&lt;/code&gt;. If you happen to don&amp;#39;t know about it, don&amp;#39;t worry and, please, fearlessly run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ man git-stash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No sweat. It might be the only intelligible Git man page of all Git man pages. But today&amp;#39;s post highlights something that doesn&amp;#39;t appear in this man 
page and I that didn&amp;#39;t know until minutes ago. I thought it might be cool to share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, &lt;code&gt;git-stash&lt;/code&gt; lets you save the current state of your working directory away and enjoy a pristine working directory that points to &lt;code&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt; 
afterwards. Those stashed local modifications can be listed, inspected and applied on top of a particular commit. They are stored in &lt;code&gt;refs/stash&lt;/code&gt; and they
can be referenced using standard reflog syntax, e.g. &lt;code&gt;stash{0}&lt;/code&gt; for the last saved stash, &lt;code&gt;stash{1}&lt;/code&gt; for the previous. &lt;code&gt;stash{2.hours.ago}&lt;/code&gt; is also possible. Slick. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for example, if you want to inspect the penultimate stash, you go like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git stash show -p stash@{1}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get something along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="highlight diff"&gt;&lt;span class="gh"&gt;diff --git a/source.rb b/source.rb
index e69de29..a5c8076 100644
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gd"&gt;--- a/index.html
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gi"&gt;+++ b/index.html
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;@@ -0,0 +1 @@
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="gi"&gt;+An important diff.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing particularly esoteric here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, though, it seems that &lt;strong&gt;you can&amp;#39;t see the diffstat for stashed untracked files&lt;/strong&gt; going like that. If you stashed untracked files with 
&lt;code&gt;git stash -u&lt;/code&gt; along with other local changes, running &lt;code&gt;git stash show -p stash@{n}&lt;/code&gt; won&amp;#39;t show any pleasant results. What the heck? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that what happens is not documented anywhere but can be inferred 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/git/git/commit/787513027a7d0af3c2cd2f04b85bc7136d580586"&gt;by looking at the commit that introduced the -u functionality&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; or by running
&lt;code&gt;git log --graph stash@{0}&lt;/code&gt; that prints out something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="highlight plaintext"&gt;*-.   commit 3dac63a4f4c0db4167b1f73699ed15ed6f0e9189
|\ \  Merge: 01adf14 7e6b4ff feab0b4
| | | Author: svankmajer &amp;lt;svankmajer@svankmajer.net&amp;gt;
| | | Date:   Wed Jun 4 16:09:03 2014 -0300
| | | 
| | |     WIP on master: 01adf14 Initial commit.
| | |    
| | * commit feab0b459862a383886a4b746f1827dd4630fb2d
| |   Author: svankmajer &amp;lt;svankmajer@svankmajer.net&amp;gt;
| |   Date:   Wed Jun 4 16:09:03 2014 -0300
| |   
| |       untracked files on master: 01adf14 Initial commit.
| |   
| * commit 7e6b4fff39516454ceb2fef244ce5db6ed6f4aca
|/  Author: svankmajer &amp;lt;svankmajer@svankmajer.net&amp;gt;
|   Date:   Wed Jun 4 16:09:03 2014 -0300
|   
|       index on master: 01adf14 Initial commit.
|  
* commit 01adf14673212f4bdab771eb11b2f42f84e57df3
  Author: svankmajer &amp;lt;svankmajer@svankmajer.net&amp;gt;
    Date:   Wed Jun 4 16:08:26 2014 -0300

            Initial commit.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investigating a little bit on StackOverflow, I learned that &lt;strong&gt;untracked files are stored in the third parent of a stash commit&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, stash@{0} has three 
parents. The first parent was the HEAD of the tree at the moment of &lt;code&gt;git stash save&lt;/code&gt;. The second parent stores the state of the index. The third parent 
stores the state of the untracked files in the working directory. This means that you can see the untracked part of the last stash doing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git show stash@{0}^3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also see the untracked file in the tree doing (notice the colon at the end):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git show stash@{0}^3:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m still sad that there isn&amp;#39;t a nice way to summarize the differences between staged, unstaged and untracked vs. actual state. Now I know that this is
due partly to the way stashes are re-applied. But oh well, there is nothing stopping me from creating the difftool of my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I will.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shulgin</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/03/shulgin/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/06/03/shulgin/</id>
    <published>2014-06-03T14:32:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-03T21:59:05-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday at 5pm, Alexander &amp;ldquo;Sasha&amp;rdquo; Shulgin passed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pmoriarty&lt;/code&gt; summarized on Hacker News all my feelings for Shulgin&amp;#39;s inspiring work and legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He synthesized and carefully chronicled the effects of hundreds of psychoactive compounds on himself and a small, dedicated core group of explorers of human consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His efforts were published in two massive, definitive tomes called PiHKAL[3][4] and TiKHAL[5][6], the titles of which stand for &amp;ldquo;Phenethylamines I Have Known and Loved&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Tryptamines I Have Known and Loved&amp;rdquo;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These volumes contained detailed chemical synthesis instructions for the compounds he created, along with &amp;ldquo;trip reports&amp;rdquo; and ratings[7] of the compounds&amp;#39; psychoactivity, ranging from:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLUS / MINUS (+/-) &amp;ldquo;The level of effectiveness of a drug that indicates a threshold action. If a higher dosage produces a greater response, then the plus/minus (+/-) was valid. If a higher dosage produces nothing, then this was a false positive.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLUS FOUR (++++) &amp;ldquo;A rare and precious transcendental state, which has been called a &amp;#39;peak experience&amp;#39;, a &amp;#39;religious experience,&amp;#39; &amp;#39;divine transformation,&amp;#39; a &amp;#39;state of Samadhi&amp;#39; and many other names in other cultures. It is not connected to the +1, +2, and +3 of the measuring of a drug&amp;#39;s intensity. It is a state of bliss, a participation mystique, a connectedness with both the interior and exterior universes, which has come about after the ingestion of a psychedelic drug, but which is not necessarily repeatable with a subsequent ingestion of that same drug. If a drug (or technique or process) were ever to be discovered which would consistently produce a plus four experience in all human beings, it is conceivable that it would signal the ultimate evolution, and perhaps the end of, the human experiment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His chemistry lab was DEA-licensed to handle &amp;ldquo;illegal&amp;rdquo; (scheduled) compounds, though he often synthesized entirely novel compounds which were not scheduled because neither the compounds nor the laws scheduling them existed yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shulgin tirelessly educated the public and the law-enforcement community on the effects and value of psychedelic and psychoactive compounds, and wrote a highly informative Q&amp;amp;A column.[7]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shulgin&amp;#39;s pioneering work inspired generations of chemists, self-experimenters, and explorers. He was well known, loved, and respected as one of the most highly accomplished psychedelic chemists in history. His presence and guidance will be deeply missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gate gate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Para gate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Para sam gate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Bodhi Svaha!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Godspeed, Sasha.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Psychlopedia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/31/understanding-psychlopedia/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/31/understanding-psychlopedia/</id>
    <published>2014-05-31T18:19:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-03T13:36:45-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the past weeks, I started to question myself about one of my current endeavors: &lt;a href="http://psiclopedia.svankmajer.net/"&gt;Psychlopedia&lt;/a&gt;.
I want to get a thorough comprehension of what I am trying to accomplish with the time and resources I am putting into this project. Know 
what can be done, thus find out and test what could or should be done to finally &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; what must be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No fooling around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to make clear that I don&amp;#39;t know for certain any of what I will be talking about in this post. This is an exploratory exercise to me, and it
should be so for you too, so please bear that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reading &lt;a href="http://thoughtbot.com/"&gt;thoughtbot&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://playbook.thoughtbot.com/"&gt;Playbook&lt;/a&gt; when I stumbled on Product Design Sprints, an amazing 
concept developed by the &lt;a href="http://www.gv.com/design/"&gt;Google Ventures&amp;#39; design team&lt;/a&gt;. 
Essentially, a Product Design Sprint is a technique that increases the chance of channeling efforts into meaningful and sustainable productions. 
Please read thoughtbot&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/the-product-design-sprint"&gt;amazing article&lt;/a&gt; on this subject which explains it to the detail 
perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I am stressing the following question: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f84LymEs67Y"&gt;&amp;#39;what job is the user hiring the product to do?&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;.
It is a question proposed by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clayton_M._Christensen"&gt;Clayton Christensen&lt;/a&gt;, a Business Administration professor at
Harvard Business School. Having asked myself about this not even once in my own product design path, I was really intrigued. So I grabbed my coat
and went out for a random walk (&lt;em&gt;on a Hidden Markov chain&lt;/em&gt;), my regular deep thinking session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking down Colegiales, I started to identify three possible jobs Psychlopedia in its current conception could do and do pretty well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Feed our curiosity and increase the quality of its by-products&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Connect us to others through our inner experiences&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Lessen our fear and/or anxiety towards psychonautics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am trying to finish the critical path based on these assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a work-in-progress and part of a series on product design focused on Psychlopedia, a digital archive of psychedelic experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reborn</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/29/reborn/"/>
    <id>http://rants.svankmajer.net/2014/05/29/reborn/</id>
    <published>2014-05-29T12:46:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-29T17:15:57-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>svankmajer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Great plans for the weekend! On saturday I will be attending the weekly meetup of &lt;a href="http://www.congresointeractivo.org/"&gt;Congreso Interactivo&lt;/a&gt; at 
the Barracas Public Library &lt;a href="http://www.bibliobarracas.com.ar/hacklab/"&gt;Hacklab&lt;/a&gt; here in Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CI is a &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; civic engagement organisation devoted to social research and the development of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_government"&gt;open goverment&lt;/a&gt; tools to improve the exercise of governance towards a better democracy. They have released upstanding apps like &lt;a href="http://www.elegilegi.org/"&gt;Elegilegi&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="http://www.decadavotada.com.ar/"&gt;Decada Votada&lt;/a&gt;, drawing attention of &lt;a href="http://www.lanacion.com.ar/1604004-como-votarias-siendo-diputado"&gt;local&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href="https://source.opennews.org/en-US/articles/decada-votada-news-app-track-voting-records/"&gt;international&lt;/a&gt; news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was a teenager I dream of being part of a open goverment initiative and I think this is a great opportunity for me to add up to a team effort 
towards the envision and effective implementation of an open democracy in Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M-x start-hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
